# **András Gémes**

### **Summary**

Embedded software engineer with 6 years of experience and a strong interest in cybersecurity, with <u>hands-on experience</u> in malware analysis and reverse engineering (e.g., ransomware, loaders and botnets). Certified in <u>Sec+</u>, <u>CASP+</u>/SecX, <u>CEH</u>, <u>IMBT</u> and <u>PMAT</u>. Looking to apply my technical expertise and security skills in a malware analyst or reverse engineer role.

### Work experience

#### **Rust Embedded Software Engineer**

Feb 2023 - Present

HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary

- Developing Rust and assembly tests for the Rust compiler, contributing to its ISO 26262 qualification process
- · Hardening the Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Creating customer-facing C and Rust examples for real-time operating system (RTOS) and bare-metal environments

#### **Embedded Software Engineer**

May 2018 - Jan 2023

*Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary* 

- Integrated Advanced Driver Assistance Systems (ADAS) software across various Electronic Control Units (ECUs)
- Configured, automated and evaluated Static Application Security Testing (SAST) using PC-lint and Clang-Tidy tools
- Configured memory, real-time operating system (RTOS) and Controller Area Network (CAN) software modules

#### **Skills**

Languages: C, Rust, Python 3, Assembly (AMD64/x86-64, ARM64/AArch64), Bash

Malware analysis (static): Ghidra, IDA, capa, YARA, DIE, dnSpy, readelf, objdump

Malware analysis (dynamic): x64dbg, VirtualBox, Qiling, Sysinternals, Regshot, Frida, GDB, eBPF, strace

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS

Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Embedded systems and protocols: STM32, ESP32, AURIX, Wi-Fi, CAN, SPI, UART, I2C

#### **Certifications**

**Fundamental cybersecurity:** CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX (awaiting certificate), EC-Council CEH Malware analysis: Invoke RE IMBT, TCM Security PMAT

### **Relevant projects**

- Ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches, focusing on the FunctionID and BSim features
- rustbininfo: submitting various improvements targeting the compiler version and dependency guesser
- shadow-shell: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C
- sys-scout: implementing eBPF tools in Rust and Python for dynamically analyzing malware

### **Education**

#### **MSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Feb 2016 - June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

• Master's thesis: Design and development of a solar energy utilization system

## **BSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Sept 2012 - Jan 2016

*University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary* 

• Thesis: Design and development of a multicopter-carried river sampling device